The sea of stars is dark
and cold – a very scary place.
A brave and wise king embarked
on a trip aboard a magnificent ship.
The ship glides, crossing the sea of stars.
Among these stars are an ugly
ice planet and a hot, soft planet.
During the long, long journey,
a lot of retainers, women, and children died.
The king cried,
"Why did I undertake this journey ?"
He even forgot the way home.
Then, the ship turned around and began to glide.
There were twin planets
where the ship was headed.
The goddess offered one
of them to the king and told him...
“I shall bestow upon
your people the name…"
"…Garmillas.”
If you stay by my side,
you'll grow and prosper forever.
The blessing echoed through the sea
of stars, and everyone lived happily.
Sister !
It's the Yamato !
The Yamato has come !
Yamato...
That Earth ship and
Iscandar share the same sin...
Did you call it to us...
...Sasha ?
Rapid turn at altitude 3500 !
Can you do it, Yabu ?!
The engine sounds fantastic !
We can do it !
Tasuke !
Got it !
Pay attention until it's over !
That's why you're still
sitting there, remember ?!
All guns, start firing !
Fire !
Incredible...
Space Battleship
Yamato
A New Voyage
Follow the Yamato.
Don't give the enemy a break.
They're pretty tough.
All units, throw short jabs !
Sink them with a barrage !
Can you really call that
fluttering bastard an airplane ?
Like you're one to talk !
Anyway, draw the enemy
away from the migrant fleet.
Roger !
Okay, stand up.
It's coming this way !
Prioritize the drifters in the ocean.
Save as many as possible.
Let's do it !
Shield deterioration 35%.
150 seconds until depletion.
Get the next shot ready quickly.
But if we remain in the resonant wave
much longer, it will damage our ship.
The Yamato and Hyuga will protect us.
Your Excellency, it's the Yamato.
The Yamato is....
Ranhalt's ship...
Your Excellency ! Your Excellency !
Enemy fleet above the north
pole is still holding position.
That's the enemy main fleet ?
After this much damage,
and they're still watching...
Nishina, how about sending
them our greetings ?
It's a huge ship.
Let me take some extra steps.
Calm down.
Your emotions will worsen the noise.
Remember our objective.
Bring back Iscandar as soon as possible.
This abominable planet…
…bring it to our home.
It looks like the enemy
fleet has begun withdrawing.
It's unexpectedly weak.
Pursuit order to the aerial unit ?
Wait.
Give everyone hot soup !
Elderly and children first !
You guys did so well.
Now you're safe.
You're safe.
So we meet again.
Sorry for being late, Berger.
From here on, we'll take the fight
to them, side by side with Yamato.
Now, I want everyone to take a look at this.
I apologize,
but please take a closer look.
Iscandar should have
suffered catastrophic damage...
...but the shattered pieces of the destroyed planet turned into dust, and its energy...
...vanished ?!
Not quite.
It was most likely transferred.
These spiky objects seem to be
some kind of transfer machine.
After destroying a planet, they amass and converge the energy to a single location.
I can see why our enemy's come here.
We're in the Bolzon system,
and its sun is getting old and bloated.
This is the state of the first planet Garmario as
it's been pulled by the gravity of the expanding sun.
Right now, it's...
There're too many of them.
The equator is like a field of spikes.
Total number is unknown.
The planet is dying, just like Garmillas.
That means, it's easy to destroy.
They remove and warp planets...
...as if they're playing space billiards.
So, that's how Dezariam does it, huh ?
In order to warp Iscandar,
our planet, Garmillas was...
Dezariam is going to use its cue stick again.
Garmario is about the same size as Jupiter.
That'll allow them an even longer warp.
We must stop them now, no matter what.
But we lost half our fleet.
The condition of the Deusula III is obvious,
and I heard His Excellency Desler was badly hurt.
We also have to come up with a way to save
100,000 of our fellow citizens of the migrant fleet.
Plus Starsha and her sister, too.
That's a given...
...but how are we going to fight ?
With the wave motion gun.
We'll destroy the planet
with the wave motion gun.
Garmario will be destroyed by simultaneous shots of the wave motion guns from the Yamato and Hyuga...
...before Dezariam can use it.
Kodai...
Captain, have you considered every alternative ?
That's the most effective measure
with our current strength.
How about the impact of
the planet's destruction on Iscandar ?
Iscandar's still in motion.
We have to carry out the operation
before it enters the danger zone.
That's too hasty.
I said we have no time.
You're going to use the wave motion gun in
front of Starsha of Iscandar to destroy a planet....
...as well as our enemy,
if the situation calls for it, right ?
Correct.
I'll take full responsibility for this.
Regardless of the enemy's purpose,
they destroyed Garmillas without hesitation.
We're allowed to take any countermeasures
in light of the universe's common sense.
That planet is dead with no life on it.
Whether it be Starsha, or even God,
we will surely be forgiven. Probably.
Use the wave motion gun
to destroy a planet ?!
If we're lucky, we can
wipe out the enemy fleet.
That's a big decision for Captain Kodai.
But we just made first
contact with those aliens.
Is it okay for us to be doing this ?
The fight has already begun.
With 100,000 civilians to worry about, any other
means for resolving this conflict are out of our hands…
Or so the reasoning goes.
But I thought the Yamato…
…or rather, the man
named Kodai Susumu…
…would reject such rationales.
You heard Melda's report, right ?
The Yamato will do what's necessary.
What should we do ?
We don't have any record
of an encounter with them.
It must be a part of the "Great Loss."
Who are they ?
Why are they trying to
save the lives of others...
...by staking their own lives...?
Their course is within our prediction.
0800 seconds till it enters the kill zone.
They took the bait.
Come here already.
The shockwave from Garmario's
destruction will wipe you out.
Prepare to fire the wave motion gun.
Connected to the energy channel
of the wave motion gun.
Compulsive injector operation, confirmed.
Final safety, released.
This noise...
The planet...
Sister ?!
Iscandar changed course ?!
Unknown type of energy detected at the poles.
Iscandar's turning around and accelerating.
It'll enter the kill zone
soon at breakneck speed.
At this rate, Garmario's shockwave will directly...
The line of fire is getting blocked.
They're using Iscandar as a shield.
Those above us, can you hear me ?
This is Yurisha of Iscandar speaking.
Yurisha...!
I'm going to inform you of
my sister Starsha's intentions.
Iscandar...
...please shoot it.
Iscandar has a vast
underground space called Sanktel.
Its energy lines are laid
throughout the planet like a web.
Aim at a node, and that should do it.
I'll let you know the
coordinates and penetration power.
Even though the planet's covered with the enemy's
momentum control field, a significant shock is expected.
In order to protect the people of the Garmillas migrant fleet, please raise a shield in synch with your firing.
Coordinates verified.
Wave motion excavation shell...
Shield shell...
Fire !
Sister !
Iscandar has begun accelerating.
It's leaving the kill zone !
Kodai, it's a success.
Something similar to wave motion energy
is gushing out, although it's weakening.
Starsha...
Resume countdown for the wave motion gun.
We don't have time to regroup
with the Hyuga and Asuka.
Re-calibrate Yamato’s wave
motion gun for single shot use.
Aim at the ideal point for target destruction...
Your interference ends here !
The enemy main fleet is in our line of fire !
They came back already ?!
Ignore them !
Kitano, is the firing line clear ?!
Iscandar will be hit.
I need 250 seconds !
She can't use the wave motion shield
while energizing the wave motion gun.
She won't last two minutes !
We have to cover her quickly !
Can't we go any faster ?!
We have to go around the kill zone !
The shortest time is 300 seconds !
Kodai...
Why can't we hit it ?!
Because of Iscandar's gravitational inclination.
The speed is fluctuating, so we can't
lock onto the correct modification factor.
Then get closer !
“Blood-curdling,”
is that what this is called…?
Dezariam’s thousand year dream…
It’s just within my grasp.
Of that I am sure.
Allow me to speak freely !
The enemy's firing accuracy is rising.
Please consider aborting the operation.
Now that the enemy knows our objective,
we'll have no second chance.
But...!
Captain...
If we use our energy reserves allocated for restart,
we can use the wave motion shield for 30 seconds.
But we won't be able to restart the engine.
We'll be stuck after firing the wave motion gun.
Is that alright ?
Let's do it.
Captain !
We can't waste Iscandar's
sacrifice and let this chance go !
We can't...
We can't waste...
...their trust and sacrifice.
Yamato can't.
The Yamato isn't just yours.
Depletion of the wave motion shield in twenty-nine...
Twenty-eight.
Twenty-seven.
Twenty-six.
Twenty-five.
Twenty-four.
Twenty-three.
Twenty-two.
Fifteen.
Fourteen.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Three.
Two.
Line of fire, clear. We can do it.
Fire the wave motion gun !
Shockwave arrival ! Status, irregular !
Crank up the sub engine,
and we can get away !
Engine Chief ?!
Impossible !
We used up all our energy !
I...
I bear responsibility for this…
You mean we all bear it, right ?
The responsibility isn't yours alone !
It's ours, isn't it ?
Pull back !
No way !
Even though we're on different ships...
Pull back !
No more sacrifices...
We're all in this together !
That's what all of us decided that day !
So why are you trying to
shoulder this all by yourself ?!
Don't be arrogant, Kodai Susumu !
Fly-wheel restarted...
The resonant wave from Asuka did it.
Second shockwave, incoming !
Engine power ?!
Twenty more seconds !
Just in time.
A detestable planet is defended
by detestable people after all.
You have no idea what your
accursed power will bring forth.
Emergency Order! Yamato, Shoot Iscandar!!
Episode 5
Susumu Kodai:
Yuki Mori:
Daisuke Shima:
Shiro Sanada:
Ryusuke Domon:
Miyako Kyozuka:
Heiji Bando:
Tasuke Tokugawa:
Shigeru Sakamoto:
Caroline Raiden:
Miki Saijo:
Akira Yamamoto:
Kaoru Niimi:
Yasuo Nanbu:
Yoshikazu Aihara:
Kenjiro Ohta:
Daisuke Ono
Houko Kuwashima
Kenichi Suzumura
Hochu Otsuka
Tasuku Hatanaka
Tomo Muranaka
Wataru Hatano
Nobuhiko Okamoto
Kento Ito
Chitose Morinaga
Satomi Moriya
Rie Tanaka
Aya Hisakawa
Kenji Akabane
Masato Kokubun
Yuki Chiba
Behind the sorrow...
kanashimi no ushiro de itsumo
Susumu Yamazaki:
Shiori Nagakura:
Tetsuya Kitano:
Mikage Kiryuu:
Hiroki Shinohara:
Haruo Nishina:
Analyzers:
Abelt Desler:
Gadel Talan:
Fomt Berger:
Wolf Flaken:
Gol Heini:
Yabu Sukelji:
Hilde Shultz:
Starsha:
Yurisha:
Mœlders:
Daeder:
Child Voice:
Hiroshi Tsuchida
Kazusa Amagai
Ryuichi Kijima
Eriko Nakamura
Daisuke Hirakawa
Kenta Miyake
Cho
Koichi Yamadera
Kotaro Nakamura
Junichi Suwabe
Akimitsu Takase
Setsuji Sato
Cho
Ayano Miura
Kikuko Inoue
Houko Kuwashima
Takaya Kuroda
Masuo Amada
Chitose Morinaga
...happiness is always waiting for you
tsugi wa shiawase ga matteiru
Let's turn that fairy tale into truth
sonna guuwa wo shinjitsuni kaemashou
You whisper with a spark in your eye
anata no me ga mabushisouni sasayaku
You don’t dream to get hurt
yume wo miru no wa kizutsuku tame janai
Love still shines even now
ai wa ima mo hikari
There’s only one prayer
tada hitotsu no inori
The future has already begun
mirai wa mou hajimatte iru